Someone has taken their love of sequels one step too far.
Scream 2 is a horror, mystery film directed by Wes Craven.
Two years after the Woodsboro murders, Sidney Prescott acclimates to college life while
someone donning the Ghostface costume begins a new string of killings.
Sidney Prescott, played by Neve Campbell.
Gale Weathers, played by Courteney Cox.
Dewey Riley, played by David Arquette.
Derek Feldman, played by Jerry O'Connell.
Mickey Altieri, played by Timothy Olyphant.
Randy Meeks, played by Jamie Kennedy.
Scream 2 is a 1997 American slasher film directed by Wes
Craven and written by Kevin Williamson.
It stars David Arquette, Neve Campbell, Courteney Cox, Sarah Michelle Gellar, Jamie
Kennedy, Laurie Metcalf, Jerry O'Connell, Jada Pinkett and Liev Schreiber.
A sequel to Scream (1996), it is the second
installment in the Scream film series.
Scream 2 follows the character of Sidney Prescott (Campbell), and the other survivors of the Woodsboro massacre, at the
fictional Windsor College in Ohio where they are targeted by a copycat killer using the identity of Ghostface.
Like its predecessor, Scream 2 combines the violence of the slasher genre with elements of
comedy, satire and "whodunit" mystery while satirizing the cliché of film sequels.
Williamson provided a five-page outline for a sequel to Scream when auctioning his original
script, hoping to entice bidders with the potential of buying a franchise.
Following a successful test screening of Scream and the film's financial and critical success, Dimension moved forward with the sequel while
Scream was still in theaters, with the principal cast all returning to star, Craven to direct and Beltrami to provide music.
The film faced controversy following its significant issues with plot information
leaking onto the Internet, revealing the identity of the killers.
Combined with the film's rushed schedule, the script was rewritten
often; pages were sometimes completed on the day of filming.
Scream 2 was released on December 12, 1997, by Dimension Films.
The film earned $172.4 million at the box office, and
received positive reviews from critics.
Beltrami received positive critical reception for his score for evolving the musical themes of the characters created in Scream, although
some critics claimed that the most memorable pieces from the film were created by composers Danny Elfman and Hans Zimmer.
Elfman's contribution had been specially written for the film, but Zimmer's score for Broken
Arrow (1996) was controversially used in the film, replacing Beltrami's own work.
The film's soundtrack achieved moderate sales success,
reaching number 50 on the Billboard 200.
A sequel, Scream 3, was released on February 3, 2000.
The film explores themes of mask, college, campus, sequel, slaughter.
The tone is dark and mind_bending.